Finding Aid for Dept. of History (University of Michigan) student papers, 1930-1987
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Series I
  - Lehmann, Charles F.
    - "The Gazetteer of the State of Michigan of 1838, A Review", 1948 (Box 3)
  - Lennane, Elizabeth
    - "Mackinac: From Military Post to Summer Resort", 1952 (Box 4)
      (History 183)
  - Lewis, Anthony
    - "Michigan Corporations and Jacksonian Democracy", 1940 (Box 4)
      (course 290s)
  - Lincoln, Philip T.
    - "Attitudes Toward General William Hull (A Survey) Historical Period: The War on the Detroit River in 1812", 1956 (Box 4)
  - Lowes, Vera
    - "Bibliographical Sketch and Genealogy of Joshua Maxwaring" (Box 4)
  - Lunny, Mary E.
    - "History of The First Methodist Episcopal Church, Ann Arbor, Michigan", 1937 (Box 4)
      (Michigan History)
  - McGarry, Eleanor
    - "An Annotated Bibliography for Michigan History" (Box 4)
    - "A Course of Study in Michigan History" (Box 4)
  - Maizlish, Stephen
    - "Michigan Democratic Party-Politics and the Annexation of Texas", 1968 (Box 4)
      (History 766)
  - Male, George A.
    - "The Stevens Family and the Civil War", 1949 (Box 4)
  - Mandlestamm, Allen B.
    - "Henry Carter Adams: Accountant, Philosopher, and Economist" (Box 4)
  - Markos, Mary
    - "The Development of Southfield High School" (Box 4)
    - "Austin Blair and Reconstruction: 1865-1873", 1958 (Box 4)
  - Martin, Wayne S.
    - "Alger, Luce and Schoolcraft Counties -- An Examination and Evaluation of the Materials in the Michigan Historical Collection Gathered and Filed by the Michigan Historical Records Survey of County Archives", 1947 (Box 4)
  - Mason, Xenia
    - "Cultural Development in the Early Nineteenth Century on Michigan as Illustrated by the Lyceum Movement", 1947 (Box 4)
  - Meaker, Merritt F.
    - "A History of the Northville Schools" (Box 4)
  - Miller, Betty
    - "Bibliography for Michigan History" (Box 4)
  - Morgan, Mildred
    - "Journeys and Opinions of Women Foreign Travelers in the Northwest Territory: 1820-1850" (Box 4)
  - Moss, Harry L.
    - "A History of Olivet Institute: 1844-1858", 1942 (Box 4)
  - Muzik, Edward J.
    - "The Influence of the Crosswhite Case on the Fugitive Slave Law of 1850", 1949 (Box 4)
    - "Paper on the Crosswhite Case" (Box 4)
  - Neeb, Elizabeth A.
    - "Bibliography on Early Germans in Michigan" (Box 4)
  - Norton, Clark F.
    - "Early Movements for the St. Mary's Falls Ship Canal", 1936 (Box 4)
      (History 264)
  - Norton, Harold E.
    - "Governmental and Administrative Steps Taken by the State of Michigan to Meet the Panic of 1837" (Box 4)
  - Novick, Marsha
    - "The University of Michigan and the Fifth Amendment: 1954", 1970 (Box 4)
      (History 393)
  - Notley, Beatrice
    - "The Administration of James B. Angell and Biographical Sketches of the Regents", 1949 (Box 4)
  - O'Dell, Richard
    - "Governor Crapo's Vetoes of Michigan Railroad Legislation", 1941 (Box 4)
  - O'Keefe, Kurt A.
    - "Hazen S. Pingree -- An Analysis of his Vote for Mayor and its Effect on the Municipal Elections: 1887-1897" (Box 4)
  - Oldfield, Bernice E.
    - "Public Sentiment", 1943 (History 341s) (Box 4)
    - "The Railroad Conspiracy Case", 1943 (Box 4)
      (History 335)-336
  - Oliver, Robert L.
    - "The Degree to Which the Michigan Pioneer and Historical Society Profited Successfully from its Precursor, The Historical Society of Michigan" (Box 4)
  - Palmer, Ina Belle
    - "Military Roads in Michigan, 1826-1836", 1931 (Box 4)
  - Perry, Dorothy M.
    - "Kinsley Scott Bingham" (Box 4)
  - Petaja, Audrey G.
    - "The History of School District No. 7, Royal Oak Township, Oakland County, Michigan, 1840-1846" (Box 4)
  - Peters, Kenneth Earl
    - "The Flint Sit-Down Strikes: December 30, 1936-February 11, 1937", 1963 (Box 4)
      (History 774)
    - "Forest Conservation in Michigan, 1866-1903: A Social and Legislative History", 1967 (Box 5)
      (History 773)
    - "Howard E. Merrill with the Y.M.C.A. in Russia, 1917-1919", 1968 (Box 5)
      (History 578)
  - Pitts, Willis N.
    - "A Brief Explanation of The Agreement Between Presbyterian and Congregational Churches in America with a Study of Their Attitude Toward Slavery, 1774-1860", 1940 (Box 5)
  - Platt, Myles M.
    - "Frank Murphy: Detroit's Liberal Mayor: 1930-1933", 1954 (Box 5)
  - Rehor, Daniel
    - "Poor Relief in Washtenaw County, 1836-1870", 1959 (Box 5)
    - "Public Opinion Concerning the Negro and Emancipation During the Civil War as Expressed in the Adrian Watchtower" (Box 5)
  - Reid, Robert
    - Contemporary Opinion in Michigan of the Polk Administration in the Prosecution of the Mexican War" (Box 5)
  - Rogers, Florence
    - "A Social and Economic Survey of Keweenaw County: 1840-1860", 1937 (Box 5)
  - Roush, Arelyne H.
    - "Plank Roads in Michigan: 1836-1900", 1937 (Box 5)
  - Sands, Mary Edwardine
    - "Outline and Bibliography: John Ball, Pioneer of Grand Rapids", 1944 (Box 5)
    - "William Butts Mershon and the Lumberman Memorial at Huron National Forest Near AuSable, Michigan" (Box 5)
    - "The Intellectual Aspects of Lewis Cass", 1942 (Box 5)
  - Sawyer, Sally Jo
    - "Teddy Roosevelt's Six-Cent Libel Suit", 1962 (Box 5)
  - Schaub, Theresa
    - "A History of the Ladies Library Association of Ann Arbor, 1866-1872" (Box 5)
      (History 184)
  - Schwartz, Alan
    - "The Senatorial Campaign of Henry Ford, 1918", 1965 (Box 5)
  - Seavoy, Ronald E.
    - "Isaac P. Christiancy and the Formation of the Republican Party in Michigan", 1961 (Box 5)
  - Sendler, Simson
    - "The Municipal Aid Movement in Michigan" (Box 5)
  - Serlin, Steven
    - "The Negroes in Detroit in the 1880s and Early 1890s" (Box 5)
  - Sessions, Vivian S.
    - "Ezra C. Seamen", 1946 (Box 5)
    - "The Political Equality Club of Ann Arbor, Michigan", 1946 (Box 5)
  - Slingerland, Gertrude
    - "Bibliography: Women on the Campus, 1870-1920", 1935 (Box 5)
  - Smith, Anita L.
    - "The History of The Ledger Star and its Effect on Inkster", 1957 (Box 5)
  - Sommer, Anna Louise
    - "Michigan for Sixth Graders" (Box 5)
    - "Indian Legends and Folk Lore" (Box 5)
  - Stadler, Donald
    - "Prominent Michigan Railroads in the 1830s", 1958 (Box 5)
    - "East Ypsilanti", 1958 (Box 5)
  - Stephenson, William W.
    - "The Colored Schools of Detroit, 1839-1869", 1959 (Box 6)
  - Stern, Jacqueline L.
    - "The Civil War Life of Harrison Soule" (Box 6)
  - Stoner, James M.
    - "Thomas M. Cooley and the Interstate Commerce Commission", 1950 (Box 6)
  - Sussell, Edward
    - "An Outline on the Life of Austin Blair from 1818 to 1860" (Box 6)
  - Tessem, Sylvanus T.
    - "History of Board of Regents from 1909-1929" (Box 6)
  - Tibbet, Ward E.
    - "The Grand Rapids Furniture Strike: April 19, 1911-August 19, 1911", 1941 (Box 6)
  - Travis, Helen I.
    - "Theodore Foster's Miscellaneous Thoughts A Manuscript: Report and Evaluation" (Box 6)
  - Tu, Hengtse
    - "A Comparison Between the Constitutional Conventions of 1850 and of 1907 in Regard of Their Membership", 1947 (Box 6)
  - Turnbull, Ruth L.
    - "Michigan's Progress Under John Judson Bagley: Reform Governor, 1873-1877", 1943 (Box 6)
      History 408
  - Van den Berg, Lawrence H.
    - "A Critical Estimate of the Brewer Collection", 1941 (Box 6)
  - Vander Mey, Frances
    - "A Study of the History of Holland, Michigan, from October 11, 1848 to April 25, 1849 as Reflected in the Minutes of the People's Assembly", 1943 (Box 6)
    - Minutes of the People's Assembly Vol. I, II, III (Box 6)
  - Vender Venn, Angie
    - "Tendencies in Indian Administration Under Lewis Cass as Secretary of War, 1831-1836", 1932 (Box 6)
  - Vander Werf, Gretchen
    - "The Black Legion: Michigan's 'American' Organization", 1969 (Box 6)
      (History 770)
  - Wartman, Charles J.
    - "The Railroad Conspiracy Case, 1849-1851", 1941 (Box 6)
  - Wetherell, Harold O.
    - "Early History of Mendon, Michigan, and Vicinity" (Box 6)
  - White, Alma
    - "Governor Fred M. Warner and Conservation" (Box 6)
  - White, Janet
    - "William Montague Ferry and the Protestant Mission on Mackinac Island", 1948 (Box 6)
  - White, John Patrick
    - "The Strike of Michigan Copper Workers, July 23, 1913-April 12, 1914", 1950 (Box 6)
      (History 342, 343)
  - Whittaker, Eva L.
    - "The Kalamazoo Case", 1947 (Box 6)
  - Wiese, Florence C.
    - "Early Transportation in Michigan" (Box 6)
  - Wilcox, Harold B.
    - "When Lewis Cass was Minister to France: 1836-1842", 1931 (Box 6)
  - Wilhelme, Frank
    - "The administration of Royal Samuel Copeland, Mayor of Ann Arbor, 1901-1903", 1970 (Box 6)
  - Williston, Lida T.
    - "The Attitude of the Ann Arbor Argus Towards the Spanish-American War" (Box 6)
  - Wilson, John H.
    - "The Life Of Dr. Oliver W. Van Osdel and the Influence of his Ministry at the Wealthy St. Baptist Church, Grand Rapids, Michigan", 1958 (Box 6)
  - Winney, Donald W.
    - "Michigan 1932: Roosevelt, Relief, Rum, and Reaction", 1969 (Box 6)
  - Wuggazer, Theodore, Jr.
    - "The Reform Movement" (Box 6)
  - Yolles, Bryan
    - "The Making of an Isolationist", 1971 (Box 6)
  - Young, James H.
    - "The Editorial Attitudes of Newspapers Toward Lincoln and the Civil War, Chapter II, 1860-1865" (Box 6)
  - Young, Jon L.
    - "Selected Bibliographical Aids Taken from the General Bibliography of The Pioneer Physician, Medical Cures and Theories in Relation to Society in the Early Nineteenth Century" (Box 6)
  - Zevin, Sidney
    - "Pingree Potato Patches" (Box 6)
- Series II
  - Atwater, Opal G.
    - "Life and political career of John Gibson Parkhurst", 1943 (Box 7)
      (History 341a)
  - Aubry, John C.
    - "Fraternities, literary societies, and student life at the University of Michigan, 1845-1855", 1980 (Box 7)
      (History 772)
  - Austin, Erick
    - "Turnout in Michigan, 1836-1960", 1968 (Box 7)
      (History 601)
  - Barczak, Stanley M.
    - "Racial violence in Jackson", 196- (Box 7)
  - Biggle, Lloyd, Jr.
    - "Musical life in a pioneer town; music in Ann Arbor newspapers, 1829-1844", 1949 (Box 7)
  - Brown, William
    - "Birth control in Ann Arbor, Michigan: a view of the 1930s", 1980 (Box 7)
      (missing as of 4/2001)
  - Bubniak, William
    - "The fraternity war", 1977 (Box 7)
      (English 125/035)
  - Cernak, Steven J.
    - "Steel in Detroit: Michigan Steel Corporation, Great Lakes Steel Corporation, and National Steel Corporation, 1922-1939", 1985 (Box 7)
      (Honors thesis)
  - Clive, Alan
    - "Michigan and the presidential election of 1944 a narrative account of American politics in action", 1970 (Box 7)
  - Cole, Richard
    - "A legal study of whites and blacks in the Michigan territory", 1970 (Box 7)
      (History 764)
  - Conley, Michael K.
    - "The role of water power in the industrial development of Northville, Michigan", 1971 (Box 7)
  - Cornell, Ralph
    - "Joe Louis" (Box 7)
      (History 151)
  - Dann, Marc
    - "Frank Murphy and civil service legislation in Michigan", 1980 (Box 7)
  - Dapprich, Terry
    - "The role of the University of Michigan in society in 1966", 1970s (Box 7)
  - Decker, John
    - "A study of the motivations of a more common abolitionist", 1977 (Box 7)
      (re: Elizabeth Chandler)
  - Edgerton, Ronald K.
    - "Joseph Ralston Hayden: the education of a colonist", 1969 (Box 7)
      (includes critique of paper written by J. Weldon Jones)
  - Fairman, Nancy
    - "Problems faced by the Dutch immigrants in Michigan", 1965 (Box 7)
  - Fischer, Steven
    - "The Toledo War", 1977 (Box 7)
  - Fisher, Theodore J.
    - "Communism in education: the University of Michigan", 1980 (Box 7)
  - Garcia, Janet
    - "Student hazing in the 1870s", 1977 (Box 7)
  - Gilpin, Alec R.
    - "The state census in Michigan", 1947 (Box 7)
  - Gray, Ruth
    - "Isle Royale experience, 1890-1892", 1965 (Box 7)
      (re: life in a copper mining camp)
  - Greeley, Will M.
    - "A sociological history of intercollegiate football; the case of the University of Michigan, 1880-1908", 1981 (Box 7)
      (History 466)
  - Greenblatt, Charles
    - "The heavyweight boxing championship, Joe Louis vs. James Braddock", 1977 (Box 7)
  - Hammitt, Barbara H.
    - "Society's summer sojourns; the rise of summer resorts in the Gilded Age with particular emphasis on Mackinac Island, Michigan and Long Branch, New Jersey", 1965 (Box 7)
      (History 779)
  - Hammond, Dennis
    - "The pre-battle conditions that affected the Civil War soldier", 1977 (Box 7)
  - Herman, Claudia Rogers
    - "Women in the faculty at the University of Michigan", (History 397, 1983 (Box 7)
  - Hilton, Ann E.
    - "The unexpected pioneer woman as personified by Arvilla Smith", 1968 (Box 7)
      (History 577)
  - Hirsch, Susan E.
    - "Patterns of land tenure and financing, 1874-1894, Washtenaw County, Michigan", 1968 (Box 7)
  - Hodas, Rick
    - "A history of the Young Woman's Home Association of Detroit", 1973 (Box 7)
      (re a Detroit boarding home and employment agency)
      (History 332)
  - Huizenga, Jack
    - "'We don't give a damm for the whole state of Michigan", 1960s (Box 7)
      (re: Toledo War, 1834-1835)
  - Johnson, Charles W.
    - "Public reaction to Justice Murphy's opinions in the Japanese-American cases", 1959 (Box 7)
    - "The history of the 32nd Signal Company, 46th Infantry Division, 1940-1948", 1959 (Box 7)
  - Jones, Barry C.
    - "Peter Dougherty and the foundation of Old Mission", 1977 (Box 7)
  - Kamp, Marc R.
    - "Senator Vandenberg and American foreign policy", 1977 (Box 7)
  - LaRoux, Jeff
    - "Iron River churches", 1980 (Box 7)
      (History 394)
  - Lindsey, Howard O'Dell
    - "A history of the city of Inkster, Michigan, 1820-1969" (Box 7)
  - Loeher, Charles
    - "Governor George Romney: the man, the administration" 196- (Box 7)
  - Miller, Brian
    - "Questions and answers about personal feelings of U.S. servicemen in World War Two", 1977 (Box 7)
  - Miselman, Michael
    - "The Civil War career of George A. Custer", 1965 (Box 7)
  - Mitchell, Jack
    - "John Jay Carton and the birth of General Motors", 1965 (Box 7)
  - Moore, William
    - [The Board of Regents, 1851-1871] (Box 7)
  - Moss, Randy
    - "Roy D. Chapin: leader of the Good Roads Movement, 1914-1918", 1980 (Box 7)
  - Moyer, Robin
    - "The Sweet Trials: an example of man's inhumanity to man", 1960s (Box 7)
      (History6)
  - Murphy, Dennis
    - "Reaction to Abraham Lincoln's assassination in Michigan, the Union armies, and Washington, D.C", 1977 (Box 7)
  - Patel, Vina
    - "Michigan reaction to the American occupation of the Philippine Islands", 1977 (Box 7)
  - Pekarek, Joseph
    - "Newburgh Village" (Box 7)
  - Perrizo, James E.
    - "Adrian, Michigan, 1891-1901: a study in confidence and apprehension", 1972 (Box 7)
  - Petok, Seth
    - "Midwest settlement process; the occurrence of mobility", 1977 (Box 7)
      (History 396)
  - Pegal, Madeline
    - "The White Panther Party: speaker, message, background, feedback", 1980 (Box 7)
  - Porter, T. S.
    - "The emergence of the Negro in Detroit's industry, 1916-1919", 1967 (Box 7)
      (business history seminar)
  - Price, Andrea
    - "Hazing", 1977 (Box 7)
  - Ribbens, Jack A.
    - "Grape growers of Paw Paw", 1965 (Box 7)
  - Rossman, James H.
    - "A history of Pennfield Township schools to consolidation and application for aid from the Kellogg Foundation, August 19, 1941", 1940s (Box 7)
  - Schatzle, Rita
    - "The admission of women to the University of Michigan", 1977 (Box 7)
  - Sessere, Marsha
    - "The life of a Michigan farm woman during the late nineteenth century", 1977 (Box 7)
  - Smith, Mae Bowden
    - "They came during seven decades; the Cornish people in the Keweenaw Peninsula, 1840-1910", 1965 (Box 7)
  - Steir, Daniel
    - "George Romney: can religion and politics be separated?", 1980 (Box 7)
  - Suggs, Robert
    - "The leadership of Detroit's Black ghetto", 1968 (Box 7)
  - Vine, Phyllis S.
    - "Nineteenth century campus crisis; the 'fraternity war' at the University of Michigan, 1850", 1970 (Box 7)
  - Wasem, Ruth Ellen
    - "The Michigan Democratic Party in 1948 the emergence of the liberal-labor coalition", 1978 (Box 7)
  - Wilson, Galen R.
    - "Hannah-Lay's Traverse City; an urban history", 1979 (Box 7)
      (History 700)